Peter Chappell

https://peterchappell.github.io/

Hire me and you'll get...

- 20 years experience as a website designer and developer. You also get the passion that comes with someone who loves their work and knows it well.
- Expert skills in JavaScript, CSS and HTML with many years of experience. Utilisation of
 modern, best practice approaches to web development for accessibility, cross-browser
 compatibility, cross-device compatibility, search engine optimisation and maintainability.
- Experience using a variety of **JavaScript frameworks and libraries** with a focus on writing high quality collaborative, maintainable and tested code.
- A well developed understanding of **programming** techniques across a wide range of languages, styles and frameworks. A proven ability to collaborate well with programmers.
- Excellent interaction design skills with a strong focus on the user experience.
- A creative approach to converting ideas into wireframes, prototypes and finalised designs.
- A passion for good **interface design** particularly with respect to **usability** and **accessibility**.
- Experience in understanding and acting on **user testing**, **feedback and website analytics** to improve both the usability and profitability of websites and applications.
- A background in **graphic design** with a clean design style balancing function and aesthetic.
- Project management skills working as a team leader, as part of a team and also individually.
- Excellent **communication** skills. A genuine interest in people and a positive attitude.
- Excellent **documentation** skills. Extensive experience in writing documents and reports (including design documents, quotes, briefs and user documentation).

Qualifications

2020 (in progress) Certificate in Counselling and Psychotherapeutic Studies Institute of Integrative Counselling & Psychotherapy, Dublin

Professional Diploma in UX

UX Design Institute, Dublin

1999 – 2002 Bachelor of Multimedia

Griffith University

1993 – 1996 Bachelor of Science

University of Queensland

Peter Chappell
Page 1 of 3

Career History

2017 to 2019 Intellum

Senior Software Engineer

Senior front-end engineer working primarily on learning management

software used by major tech companies around the world.

Jan - Apr 2017 **Accenture - The Dock**

Software Developer Associate Manager

Front-end developer at the Accenture Centre for Innovation in Dublin.

2014 - Sep 2016 **Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC)**

Senior developer with ABC News Digital.

Front-end development on the ABC online news products.

2013 - 2015**Thought Fort**

Partner and co-organiser of a co-working space in Brisbane.

Responsible for much of the day to day running of a co-working space.

2011 - 2014**Experience Bureau**

Freelance UI Design and Development for projects large and small.

Utilising my skills in UX, UI design, front-end web development, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, mobile web, Wordpress, graphic design and documentation.

2009 - 2011Cambia.org

Not for profit organisation developing a web application for searching patents.

Requirements, prototypes, UI design and development, graphic design.

2009 My Virtual Home

Desktop application for building a 3D model of your own home.

Front-end development, UI design and prototyping.

2008 aroundaboutway.com

Travel blog for honeymoon adventure from Dublin to Bali without flying.

Website design and build, photography, audio, writing. Logistics etc.

2003 - 2008Zolv.com

UK web design and development agency specialising in travel.

Interaction design, web design and documentation, front-end development.

1999 - 2003Digicon

Web design agency based in Brisbane, Australia.

Web designer working on a range of business and government websites.

Peter Chappell Page 2 of 3

Summary of skills

Techniques JavaScript programming using a variety of frameworks.

Front-end web development.

User interface design and development. Conception and user workflows etc.

Wireframes, HTML wireframes, rapid prototyping.

Graphic and website design.

Project management, reporting, communication.

Documentation.

Languages JavaScript (frameworks and libraries including React, Polymer, Backbone,

Ember, Angular, Jest, Mocha, Google APIs, etc).

Extensive work with Node & Ruby on Rails but with a focus on front-end

integration.

Data formats and transformers JSON, XML, XSLT etc.

HTML and CSS (keeping up to date with the best practices).

Experience working with Java, PHP, C# .Net, Django, Cold Fusion (all to a

basic level and mostly in the front-end/integration).

Software IntelliJ, VS Code (and other IDEs when needed).

Source Control including Git.

Other utilities including Linux terminal, Docker etc.

Jira, Confluence, Basecamp, Rally, Pivotal Tracker, Trello (and others).

Sketch and Adobe Creative Suite (and other graphics programs as needed).

Microsoft Office (and other packages such as Open Office and Pages etc).

Referees

Contact details of references can be supplied on request.